<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on To be the Light</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on To be the Light</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:26:21 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wlemuel.github.io/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom Annotations in Java: Creating and using your own annotations</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/09/custom-annotations-in-java-creating-and-using-your-own-annotations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:26:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/09/custom-annotations-in-java-creating-and-using-your-own-annotations/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-dot-introduction-to-annotations-in-java">
 1. Introduction to Annotations in Java
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#1-dot-introduction-to-annotations-in-java">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Annotations in Java are metadata that provide additional information about a
program element, such as a class, method, or field. Annotations are used to
provide information to the compiler or to other tools, such as code generators
or libraries, and can be used for a variety of purposes, including defining
access control, providing information about dependencies, or specifying runtime
behavior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Build Custom Container Images with Podman</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/08/how-to-build-custom-container-images-with-podman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 13:29:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/08/how-to-build-custom-container-images-with-podman/</guid><description>&lt;p>Containers have become an increasingly popular tool for developers and sysadmins
to package and deploy applications in a scalable and efficient manner. One of
the key benefits of containers is that they allow for the creation of custom
images, which can be tailored to meet specific application requirements. In this
article, we will explore how to build custom container images using Podman, a
popular open-source tool for managing containers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-dot-understanding-container-images">
 1. Understanding Container Images
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#1-dot-understanding-container-images">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A container image is a lightweight, stand-alone, and executable package of
software that includes everything needed to run a piece of software, including
the code, runtime, libraries, environment variables, and system tools. Container
images are designed to be portable and can be run on any system that supports
containers, making it easy to deploy applications across multiple environments.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>