<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on To be the Light</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on To be the Light</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:52:36 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wlemuel.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comparing Nginx and Caddy: Which Web Server is Right for Your Needs?</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/03/comparing-nginx-and-caddy-which-web-server-is-right-for-your-needs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:52:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/03/comparing-nginx-and-caddy-which-web-server-is-right-for-your-needs/</guid><description>When it comes to choosing a web server, there are many options available, each with its own set of features and advantages. Two of the most popular web servers are Nginx and Caddy, both of which have gained a strong following among developers. In this article, we will compare Nginx and Caddy to help you decide which one is right for your needs.
1. Features Nginx is a feature-rich web server that supports a wide range of protocols and can be used for a variety of applications.</description></item><item><title>Software Development Trends and Their Impact on the Industry</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/01/software-development-trends-and-their-impact-on-the-industry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 21:36:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2023/02/01/software-development-trends-and-their-impact-on-the-industry/</guid><description>Software development is a constantly evolving field, and new trends emerge every year that shape the way software is designed, developed, and used. In this article, we will discuss the latest software development trends and their impact on the industry.
1. Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) are becoming increasingly popular in software development. AI and ML algorithms can analyze vast amounts of data, automate repetitive tasks, and provide intelligent insights and recommendations.</description></item><item><title>Tracking down where disk space has gone on Linux</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2020/09/15/tracking-down-where-disk-space-has-gone-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 15:53:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2020/09/15/tracking-down-where-disk-space-has-gone-on-linux/</guid><description>One of my linux server shows that it has low disk usage right now, so I decide to free disk space by deleting some useless files, including expired logs. At first I connect to remote linux server with ssh, and then do the following steps:
1. Show the disk space information. df -h # Filesystem Size Used Avail Use% Mounted on # /dev/vda1 40G 33G 4.5G 89% / # devtmpfs 1.</description></item><item><title>Make TeamViewer Work on Arch Linux</title><link>https://wlemuel.github.io/2020/03/09/make-teamviewer-work-on-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 15:36:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://wlemuel.github.io/2020/03/09/make-teamviewer-work-on-arch-linux/</guid><description>Problem Description I was trying to setup TeamViewer 15.4 on Arch (manjaro) Linux in office, so that I could remotely connect to it from my home computer, which is a MacBook also running TeamViewer. I had all the login credentials and stuff, but TeamViewer on ArchLinux said &amp;ldquo;Not Ready, Please check your connection&amp;rdquo;. It won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to log in or attempt to connect to anything.
Then I checked the Internet connection, all worked fine.</description></item></channel></rss>